<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | My Learning Journey</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 16:07:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python with Excel Workbook</title>
      <link>/post/3may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 16:07:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/3may/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been hectic past one month, with circuit breaker , technical assessment and interviews. I would say I have learnt something in each assessment although some of them are really tough. In this post, I will be sharing on working on Python and Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pandas has integrated the capability of reading Excel file is really convenient to use. One of the assessment which I have done requires me to perform EDA on Excel file and create charts report in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;#read excel file
df_policy = pd.read_excel(&#39;PREMIUM_POLICY_DATA.xlsb&#39;,sheet_name=&#39;POLICY&#39;, engine=&#39;pyxlsb&#39;)
df_premium = pd.read_excel(&#39;PREMIUM_POLICY_DATA.xlsb&#39;,sheet_name=&#39;PREMIUM&#39;, engine=&#39;pyxlsb&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engine pyxlsb is used to support for binary Excel files. It was released in on the &lt;code&gt;1.0.0&lt;/code&gt; release of pandas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, I created a plot and pin in one worksheet and copy the output data into another sheet. Here is a sample visualisation that I have appended and below is a function I have wrote to append this chart into the sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/3May/download.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps to create a excelwork and worksheet and append image&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Import these libraries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Import io&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;import xlsxwriter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from openpyxl import load_workbook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to use package xlsxwriter to create a workbook. Create the worksheets which are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instantiate an io for image data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a function/ run seperate codeline to create a plot and append the position you need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close the workbook to save the image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#creating a workbook excel file
workbook = xlsxwriter.Workbook(&#39;report.xlsx&#39;)
wks2=workbook.add_worksheet(&#39;report_chart&#39;)
#wks1=workbook.add_worksheet(&#39;Overview_chart&#39;)


#create io for image data for inserting charts
imgdata=io.BytesIO()

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;# function to load dataframe, plot, insert imagedata io into excel with position
def plot_m(df,imagedata,wk,a,b,title):
  	#matplotlib
    df.plot(kind=&#39;bar&#39;,x=&amp;quot;MonthName&amp;quot;)
    plt.legend()
    plt.xticks(rotation=0)
    plt.xlabel(&amp;quot;Month&amp;quot;)
    plt.ylabel(&amp;quot;GWP($)&amp;quot;)
    #set title
    plt.title(title)
    #set currentfigure size
    plt.gcf().set_size_inches(8, 7)
    #save image
    plt.savefig(imagedata, format=&#39;png&#39;)
    #insert image into workbook
    #a and b refers to position of the image in the worksheet
    wk.insert_image(a,b, &#39;&#39;, {&#39;image_data&#39;: imagedata})
   
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to save the workbook images, you will need to remember to close the workbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;# close workbook to save the files
workbook.close()

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps to append data into workbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the workbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use pandas function to insert dataframe into worksheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;#load workbook to save the data into other worksheets
book = load_workbook(&#39;report.xlsx&#39;)
writer = pd.ExcelWriter(&#39;report.xlsx&#39;, engine=&#39;openpyxl&#39;)
writer.book = book

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have perform a try-except if the data is empty dataframe, I will pass to prevent throwing error if the dataframe is empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;try: 
  # writing the dataframe into excel and naming the worksheet &amp;quot;GWP_booking_thisyr&amp;quot;
    booked_ty_plt.to_excel(writer, &amp;quot;GWP_booking_thisyr&amp;quot;)
except:
    pass
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least remember to save the written data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;writer.save()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this assessment, I understood that Python and Excel can work hand-in-hand and we could  be generating reports automatically with Python scripts like this. Anyway, there is more requirement needed for the technical assessment, I would share the second half of the assessment in another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing MongoDb with Pymongo</title>
      <link>/post/9apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:27:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/9apr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the midst of looking for a job in such situation, I took some time to pick up new knowledge which I think it&#39;s useful. One of them is &lt;strong&gt;MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MongoDB is a document-oriented NoSQL database used for high volume data storage. MongoDB is a database which came into light around the mid-2000s. It falls under the category of a NoSQL database. Traditional RDBMS uses SQL syntax to store and retrieve data for further insights. Instead, a NoSQL database system encompasses a wide range of database technologies that can store structured, semi-structured, unstructured and polymorphic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is NoSQL?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NoSQL is a non-relational database that does not require a fixed schema,avoid joins and is easy to scale. NoSQL database stands for &amp;ldquo;Not Only SQL&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Not SQL.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why NoSQL?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structured SQL is difficult to scale as database grows. Unstructured databases do not need to follow predefined format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways of installing MongoDB on the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have chose to install them using HomeBrew and largely uses Command Line to interact with MongoDB. There are some things you may need to watch out like Os version of your Mac. You may wish to follow this installation guide. This guide makes it easy to understand and follow like &lt;a href=&#34;https://zellwk.com/blog/local-mongodb/&#34;&gt;creating a connection on local machine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is also another way which is to install MongoDB Compass on the local machine. You may wish to follow this &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.mongodb.com/compass/master/install/&#34;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-with-mongodb&#34;&gt;Python with MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In python, in order to connect to MongoDB, we will need a package call PyMongo. Assuming installation is done correctly, now we will move on to Python to connect to our database. MongoDB works in the key value pair metholody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below snippet is the basic of connecting to the database. The package &amp;ldquo;pprint&amp;rdquo; is called pretty printer which allows user to print data in a more readable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import pymongo 
import pprint
mongo_uri = &amp;quot;mongodb://localhost:27017/&amp;quot;  
client = pymongo.MongoClient(mongo_uri)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see available databases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;client.list_database_names()

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating Database and collection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is simple to create a database and a collection in python with the following syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;mydb=client[&#39;sample&#39;]
mytable=mydb[&#39;table&#39;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this database and collection will not be shown if we run list_database_names() module. This is because MongoDB does not show any empty databases. We will need to insert arbitrary data into the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;testInsert=mytable.insert_one({&amp;quot;country&amp;quot;:&#39;India&#39;}).inserted_id

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also use pandas to load a csv and transform into MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;df=pd.read_csv(&#39;sampleMongoData.csv&#39;) 
#create empty array
listofDocs=[]
for i in df.index:
    listofDocs.append(dict(df.iloc[i]))

myfinal = mytable.insert_many(listofDocs)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading from MongoDB and transfer to a dataframe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;# transfering to dataframe
sample=table.find()
df=pd.DataFrame(sample)
df.head()

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inserting mutliple observations into MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;mport datetime
new_posts = [{&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;newMike&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;username&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;latestpost!&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;date&amp;quot;: datetime.datetime(2009, 11, 12, 11, 14)},
            {&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Eliot&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;onceAgain&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;text&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;and pretty easy too!&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;date&amp;quot;: datetime.datetime(2009, 11, 10, 10, 45)}]

final = mytable.insert_many(new_posts)

final.inserted_ids
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon successful data entry, this will be shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;[ObjectId(&#39;5e8c2ebc6057435b48b52886&#39;), ObjectId(&#39;5e8c2ebc6057435b48b52887&#39;)]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filtering entry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to filter an entry of document, you will need to use find_one method&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;mytable.find_one({&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&#39;Same&#39;})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete entry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To delete entry, you will just need to use delete_one method&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mytable.delete_one({&#39;name&#39;:&#39;Mike&#39;})

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update entry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update entry, you will to use the update_one method&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;myquery = { &amp;quot;address&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Valley 345&amp;quot; }
newvalues = { &amp;quot;$set&amp;quot;: { &amp;quot;address&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Canyon 123&amp;quot; } }

mytable.update_one(myquery, newvalues)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope the resources and this post willl be able to show you the basics of MongoDB and how you can try to integrate Python with MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2020/02/mongodb-in-python-tutorial-for-beginners-using-pymongo/&#34;&gt;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2020/02/mongodb-in-python-tutorial-for-beginners-using-pymongo/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guru99.com/create-read-update-operations-mongodb.html&#34;&gt;https://www.guru99.com/create-read-update-operations-mongodb.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zellwk.com/blog/install-mongodb/&#34;&gt;https://zellwk.com/blog/install-mongodb/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capstone Project</title>
      <link>/post/30mar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 10:23:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/30mar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hotel-pal-a-content-based-recommender&#34;&gt;Hotel Pal: A Content-based recommender&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be sharing my thoughts about the project, the challenges I have faced and after thoughts of this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of GA curriculum, I built a end-to-end content based recommender engine, deployment on Heroku via Flask. The objective is to transform implicit information provided by users into explicit features for hotel recommendation system engine. There are two parts to this recommender engine using hotel attributes and reviews by users respectively to build two separate recommendation engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a very general way, recommender systems are algorithms aimed at suggesting relevant items to users (items being movies to watch, text to read, products to buy or anything else depending on industries).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are two main data selection methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborative-filtering: In collaborative-filtering items are recommended, for example hotels, based on how similar your user profile is to other users’, finds the users that are most similar to you and then recommends items that they have shown a preference for. This method suffers from the so-called cold-start problem: If there is a new hotel, no-one else would’ve yet liked or watched it, so you’re not going to have this in your list of recommended hotels, even if you’d love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content-based filtering: This method uses attributes of the content to recommend similar content. It doesn’t have a cold-start problem because it works through attributes or tags of the content, such as views, Wi-Fi or room types, so that new hotels can be recommended right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of content-based is that we have to know the content of both user and item. Usually you construct user-profile and item-profile using the content of shared attribute space. For example, for a movie, you represent it with the movie stars in it and the genres (using a binary coding for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a number of popular encoding schemes but the main ones are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-hot encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Term frequency–inverse document frequency (TF-IDF) encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word embeddings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we will be discussing content-based filtering of recommender engine, turning implicit attributes into explicit features for hotel recommender engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details can be found on my github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alantancr/Hotel-Recommender&#34;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thought-process&#34;&gt;My thought process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share my experience in terms of the  process of this capstone. As a beginner in data science project, the first challenge I have faced was selecting the appropriate topic to work on and capturing the end goal of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being objective and selecting a digestible topic within timeline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With given about 4-5 weeks timeline, I took consideration of choosing a topic which I could complete on time.  Since I was always interested about how Netflix throws us recomendations of movies/shows we might like, I zoomed into looking at recommender systems. The recommender was introduced as part of unsupervised machine learning techniques in the course around week 7-8, so I have sufficient time to read up and do my research on building recommender engine. It took me around 2-3 weeks to settle in on a topic which I want to work on and how my project demostration will look like. The  difficult part is to conceptualise how the demostration will look like, what information to use and illustrate on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals of  project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took consideration of building a demo as part of my consideration for the project. Because with the aid of demo, it will be helpful for my audience to understand what I am trying to deliver. From project managment perspective, I inked down the various timeline I need to meet in order the final deadline. I also evaluated the difficulty of each task, giving more time for deployment since it was my first time deploying on Flask and using Heroku. Base on my experience on deployment when i was doing my Graduate Diploma, the deployment is the phase where I did a lot of self reading and debugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical perspect of the project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key issues which I faced initially when I was writing the code to compile a sparse matrix and tabulating a cosine-similar matrix was computation power. My current MacBook has only 8gb Ram and some codes takes a bit of computation power. I explored Google Colab and Sagemaker, and as recommended by TA, AWS Sagemaker is so much efficient and easy to use. It has exactly the same user interface as jupyter notebook. Moreover, the better computation specifications is not really costly as  long as you remember to turn off the instance after usage.  3-4 hours of a ml.t2.2xlarge (32gb ram) cost me about 3-4 USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the deployment phase, there are guides available online and it is really useful. One of the website which i followed diligently is this &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackabuse.com/deploying-a-flask-application-to-heroku/&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;. I felt that the most challenging part was the http protocols, GET and POST requests and how information are passed through these requests. Fortunately, I have tapped on my past experience in software development to build the site. I have considered using a docker and host in AWS but utlimately my application is not intensive. I felt Heroku works for me now and it&#39;s free anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;looking-back&#34;&gt;Looking back&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journey was really interesting. I learnt to look at problems in a different perspective and building an end-to end solution needs to go through a lot more thought process. I tried different technology and see how it work or did not work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation!!!</title>
      <link>/post/20mar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/20mar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beginning-of-a-new-journey&#34;&gt;Beginning of a new journey&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 12 weeks zoomed past so quickly. It is a beginning of a new journey. I shall take this opportunity to thank the teaching team and classmates/friends of DSI12 for this wonderful journey. I shall write a post about my capstone project in another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/20mar/classphoto.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alternative text for search engines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folium and Kyso</title>
      <link>/post/29feb/29febpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/29feb/29febpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time zoomed past so quickly. I am into the last two weeks of the GA program and capstone submission is round the corner.  While doing my research for capstone, I have learnt and discovered more stuff about Python, deployment and even AWS services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much research, I have discovered a way to render interactive charts on markdown on static site. There is another application, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kyso.io/&#34;&gt;Kyso.io&lt;/a&gt; for users to upload their data science journal (e.g. Jupyter notebooks). It allows you to hide your code and render charts as you want. Thereafter, you can embed this iFrame into the markdown which can be rendered into html.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 is the hottest topic of the world. I really hope that the situation improves and the world resumes business as usual. May those who are infected recover and get well soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have downloaded the dataset of  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/imdevskp/corona-virus-report&#34;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/a&gt; from Kaggle and plotted this interactive chart to try embedding interactive charts on my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the below chart, I have plotted out the number of confirmed cases as of 27 February globally using Folium.Python Folium library has been a helpful resource for me to utilize the power of geospatial visual analysis. Geospatial data analysis provides another dimension in a single visualisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shall share more about my capstone the next post&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://kyso.io/alantancr/technical-analysisipynb/embed#code=hidden&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;400px&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stylecloud, another means to create creative WordCloud</title>
      <link>/post/01feb2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 06:11:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/01feb2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-journey-at-ga&#34;&gt;Learning Journey at GA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a hectic 6 weeks and time passed very quickly. There were so much to learn in my data science journey. So far, these were the topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression metholody&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification metholody&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the recent project, we were tasked to perform scrap subreddits and perform classification analysis. I have also learnt how to create interesting wordcloud through my research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found &lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/generate-modern-stylish-wordcloud-with-stylecloud-9cbb059696d2&#34;&gt;this interesting package&lt;/a&gt; which makes masking of wordcloud so simple. It makes visualisation so easy and cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After using stylecloud package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/1feb/reddit.png&#34; alt=&#34;alternative text for search engines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/1feb/fitness.png&#34; alt=&#34;alternative text for search engines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/1feb/mentalhealth.png&#34; alt=&#34;alternative text for search engines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is original wordcloud :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/1feb/mh.png&#34; alt=&#34;alternative text for search engines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/1feb/fit.png&#34; alt=&#34;alternative text for search engines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I start to write my Hugo theme blog</title>
      <link>/post/05jan2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:25:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/05jan2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-creating-this-post&#34;&gt;Why am I creating this post?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt that it will be a way to jot down my experiences while creating this blog, this will allow me to share my thoughts. After  &amp;lsquo;googling&amp;rsquo;, it was not as intimidating as I thought. I was surprised that it was simpler than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup-you-need-to-create-beforehand&#34;&gt;Setup you need to create beforehand&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; (It&#39;s free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; (It&#39;s free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-may-need-to-read-up-some-of-the-following&#34;&gt;You may need to read up some of the following&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are basics git commands that we need to know, learn more from &lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/10-git-commands-that-will-get-you-started-right-now-94d814761919&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RBlogdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have referenced steps from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.storybench.org/how-to-build-a-website-with-blogdown-in-r/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on how to use RStudio and RBlogdown to create this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos Martin! He had made creating blog using R so simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
